石破天惊-Sptj.mhw
加勒比海盗2-聚魂棺
Will!
威尔
Why is this happening? I don't know.
这是怎么回事? 我不知道
You look beautiful.
你看起来真美
It's bad luck for the groom to see the bride before the wedding.
婚礼前让新郎见到新娘是厄运之兆
Make way! Let me through! How dare you!
闪开 让我过去 大胆
Stand your men down at once. Do you hear me?
马上让你的人滚蛋 听见没?
Governor Weatherby Swann, it's been too long.
韦瑟比・斯旺总督 久违啦
Cutler Beckett? It's Lord now, actually.
卡特勒・贝克特? 现在是贝克特勋爵了
Lord or not, you have no reason and no authority to arrest this man.
不管你是不是勋爵 你没有理由 也没有权利逮捕这位先生
In fact, I do. Mr Mercer?
事实上 我有 玛萨先生?
The warrant for the arrest of one William Turner.
我有授权 逮捕人犯威廉・特纳
This warrant is for Elizabeth Swann. Is it? That's annoying. My mistake.
这个逮捕证是伊丽莎白・斯旺的 是吗?真麻烦 是我的错
Arrest her. On what charges?
把她抓起来 罪名是什么?
Aha. Here's the one for William Turner.
这是威廉・特纳的
And I have another one for a Mr James Norrington.
我还有另外一张 是詹姆斯・诺灵顿先生的
Is he present? What are the charges?
他在这吗? 罪名是什么?
Commodore Norrington resigned his commission some months ago.
诺灵顿司令官数月前辞职了
That wasn't the answer to the question I asked.
我觉得这不是我要问的
Lord Beckett. In the category of questions not answered...
贝克特勋爵 你的问题没人回答
We are under the jurisdiction of the king's governor of Port Royal
我们归国王在皇家港的总督管辖
and you will tell us what we are charged with.
你得说清楚我们的罪名是什么
The charge is "conspiring to set free
罪名是…
a man convicted of crimes against the Crown and Empire
阴谋释放一名触犯了帝国法律的死囚
and condemned to death, for which the..."
而对此…
For which the punishment, regrettably, is also death.
而对此的惩罚 很遗憾 也是死刑
Perhaps you remember a certain pirate named Jack Sparrow.
也许你们还记得某个 名叫杰克・斯派洛的海盗
Captain.
船长
Captain Jack Sparrow.
杰克・斯派洛船长
Yes, I thought you might.
没错 我就知道你们记得
Fifteen men on a dead man's chest
亡灵箱上十五人坐
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum
嘿呦吼吼 来瓶朗姆酒
Drink and the devil had done for the rest
干一杯啊 剩下的留给魔鬼
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum
嘿呦吼吼 来瓶朗姆酒
Prisoners, come on!
囚犯们 过来
Sorry, mate.
兄弟 对不起啦
Mind if we make a little side trip?
介意陪我一游吗?
I didn't think so.
我想你不会介意
Not quite according to plan. Complications arose, ensued, were overcome.
似乎计划有变? 临时有变 还好我随机应变
You got what you went in for, then?
你找到要找的东西了吗?
Captain, I think the crew, meaning me as well,
船长 我觉得船员们 也包括我
were expecting something a bit more shiny,
我们想要些亮闪闪的东西
with the Isla de Muerta going pear-shaped, reclaimed by the sea with the treasure.
如果死亡岛 带着上面的财宝 又沉入大海怎么办?
And the Royal Navy chasing us around the Atlantic.
皇家海军还在满大西洋上追我们
And the hurricane. Aye.
还有飓风 是啊 是啊
All in all, it seems some time since we did a speck of honest pirating.
总之 我们似乎有一阵没干海盗的本行啦
Shiny. Aye, shiny.
闪亮的? 没错 闪亮的
Is that how you're all feeling?
这就是你们想要的吗?
That perhaps dear old Jack is not serving your best interests as captain?
也许老杰克没兴趣当你们的船长
Walk the plank.
啊 走木板吧
What did the bird say? Do not blame the bird.
那鸟说啥? 别怨鸟了
Show us what is on that piece of cloth there.
给我们看看那块布上有什么
You know that don't do no good. It does me.
这么干可不好 对我来说不错
It's a key. No. Much more better.
是把钥匙 不 钥匙怎么比得上这个
It is a drawing of a key.
这可是一把钥匙的图样
Gentlemen,
先生们
what do keys do?
钥匙是用来干嘛的呢?
Keys
钥匙
unlock things?
能开锁?
And whatever this key unlocks, inside there's something valuable.
不管这钥匙开的是什么锁 里面一定有值钱的东西
So we're setting out to find whatever this key unlocks.
所以我们要出发找到这钥匙能开的锁?
No.
不对
If we don't have the key, we can't open whatever we don't have that it unlocks.
没有它 不管那是什么锁 我们也打不开
So what purpose would be served in finding whatever need be unlocked,
不先搞到钥匙 找到锁又有何用?
which we don't have, without first having found the key what unlocks it?
且不说咱们手上还没锁！
So we're going after this key.
就是说…我们要找钥匙罗?
You're not making any sense at all.
你的话完全不合理
Any more questions?
还有什么问题吗?
So do we have a heading?
那 我们有航向吗?
A heading.
啊 航向
Set sail in a
升帆向…
general
大概…
that-way direction.
朝那个方向
Captain?
船长?
Come on, snap to and make sail. You know how this works. Go on.
快点起航 你们知道怎么做
Have you noticed lately
你注意到了没有?
the captain seems to be acting a bit strange... er?
船长好像有点怪
Setting sail without knowing his own heading.
连航向都不知道就起航
Something's got Jack vexed, and mark my words,
肯定有什么东西让他心事重重
what bodes ill for Jack Sparrow bodes ill for us all.
要我说 杰克・斯派洛都不知所措 一定不是好兆头
Lord Beckett, the prisoner as ordered, sir.
贝克特勋爵 囚犯带到
Those won't be necessary.
去掉镣铐
The East India Trading Company has need of your services.
东印度公司需要你的服务
We wish for you to act as our agent
我们希望你可以作为我们的代理人
in a business transaction with our mutual friend Captain Sparrow.
和我们共同的朋友斯派洛船长谈笔生意
More acquaintance. How do you know him?
我们只是认识 谈不上是朋友 你怎么认识他的?
We've had dealings in the past.
我们过去打过交道
And we've each left our mark on the other.
我们都给对方留下了自己的印记
What mark did he leave on you?
他给你留下什么印记了?
By your efforts, Jack Sparrow was set free.
因为你 杰克・斯派洛才得到自由
I would like you to go to him
我想要你找到他
and recover a certain property in his possession.
从他那拿件财物回来
Recover. At the point of a sword?
拿回?用剑逼他吗?
Bargain.
谈条件
Letters of marque.
私掠许可
You will offer what amounts to a full pardon.
你的刑罚将被完全赦免
Jack will be free, a privateer in the employ of England.
杰克将获得自由 成为英国雇佣的私掠船长
Somehow I doubt Jack will consider employment the same as being free.
我有点怀疑杰克会认为 雇佣等同于自由
Freedom.
自由
Jack Sparrow is a dying breed.
杰克・斯派洛这类人必将消亡
The world is shrinking,
世界越来越小了
the blank edges of the map filled in.
地图边界的上空白越来越少
Jack must find his place in the New World or perish.
杰克要不就在新世界找到自己的位置 不然就死路一条
Not unlike you, Mr Turner.
你和他不同 特纳先生
You and your fiancee face the hangman's noose.
你和你的未婚妻将面临绞刑
So you get Jack and the Black Pearl. The Black Pearl?
就是说杰克和黑珍珠号你都要? 黑珍珠号?
The property you want that he possesses. A ship? Hardly.
你要他的船 一条船?
The item in question is considerably smaller and far more valuable,
我要的东西要小得多 但也值钱得多
something Sparrow keeps on his person at all times.
斯派洛总是随身带着的一件东西
A compass?
一个罗盘
You know it.
你知道这件东西
Bring back that compass or there's no deal.
把那罗盘弄回来 不然这交易就作废
Why is the rum always gone?
怎么朗姆酒总是喝光?
That's why.
原来这么回事
As you were, gents.
继续 先生们
Time's run out, Jack.
时光飞逝啊 杰克
Bootstrap.
靴带
Bill Turner.
比尔・特纳
You look good, Jack.
你看上去不错啊 杰克
Is this a dream?
这是梦吗?
No.
不是
I thought not. If it were, there'd be rum.
我想也不是 不然就会有朗姆酒了
You got the Pearl back, I see.
看来你夺回"珍珠"了
I had some help retrieving the Pearl, by the way.
有人帮我夺回了"珍珠"号
Your son.
你的儿子
William?
威廉?
He ended up a pirate after all.
最后还是干上了海盗
And to what do I owe the pleasure of your carbuncle?
我欠你这老瘤子什么情吗?
He sent me.
是"他"派我来的
Davy Jones.
戴维・琼斯
So it's you, then.
啊 原来是这样
He shanghaied you into service, eh?
他把你骗上贼船的 对吧?
I chose it.
我选的
I'm sorry for the part I played in the mutiny against you, Jack.
我很抱歉 针对你的那次叛乱中 我没干什么好事 杰克
I stood up for you.
我是支持你的
Everything went wrong after that.
那之后一切都乱套了
They strapped me to a cannon. I ended up on the bottom of the ocean,
他们把我绑到一尊大炮上 沉到海底
the weight of the water crushing down on me.
海水压得我死死的
Unable to move.
动也动不了
Unable to die, Jack.
死也死不成 杰克
And I thought that even the tiniest hope of escaping this fate, I would take it.
即使是一丝能摆脱这种命运的机会 我也会抓住不放的
I would trade anything for it.
我会用一切来交换的
It's funny what a man will do to forestall his final judgment.
一个人为了逃避最终审判 真是什么事都干得出啊
You made a deal with him too, Jack.
你也和他做了交易 杰克
He raised the Pearl from the depths for you.
他替你将"珍珠"号从海底拉了上来
13 years, you've been her captain.
你可是做了它13年的船长
Technically... Jack.
准确来说… 杰克
You won't be able to talk yourself out of this.
靠嘴皮子你是甩不脱的
The terms what applied to me apply to you as well.
对我适用的条款 对你也适用
One soul bound to crew 100 years upon his ship.
有个灵魂 注定要在这船上服务一百年
The Flying Dutchman already has a captain...
"飞翔的荷兰人" 已经有个船长
Then it's the locker for you!
所以你也跑不了
Jones's terrible leviathan will find you
琼斯的大海怪会找到你的
and drag the Pearl back to the depths and you along with it.
把你和"珍珠"号一起拖回海底
Any idea when Jones might release said terrible beastie?
你知道琼斯什么时候 会派所谓的大海怪来吗?
I already told you, Jack.
我告诉过你了 杰克
Your time is up.
你的劫数已尽
It comes now,
它现在就来了
drawn with ravenous hunger to the man what bears the black spot.
如饿鬼般的贪婪 直奔带有黑斑的人
On deck, all hands! Make fast the bunt gasket!
所有人上甲板 赶快拉紧束帆索
On deck! Scurry!
小子们 快点
Scurry! I want movement! Movement! I want movement!
快点 快起航
Lift the skin up! Keep your loof! Haul those sheets!
起帆 稳舵 扬帆
Run them! Run! Keep running! Run as if the devil himself and itself is upon us!
跑 快跑 恶魔就追在我们后面
Do we have a heading? Run! Land.
我们有航向吗? 启动 朝向陆地
Which port? I didn't say "port", I said "land". Any land.
哪个港口? 我没说港口 我说的是陆地 任何陆地
Jack's hat! Bring her about! No, no!
杰克的帽子 弄上来 别,别
Leave it!
别管那个了
Run.
快跑
Back to your stations, the lot of you!
回到岗位上去 都回去
Jack?
杰克?
For the love of mother and child, Jack, what's coming after us?
看在圣母和圣子的份上 到底是什么东西在追我们啊?
Nothing.
没什么
Here, now, you can't be here. I think you'll find he can.
你不能待在这儿 你会知道他可以待在这
Mr Swann!
斯旺先生
Governor Swann, still.
我还是斯旺总督
Do you think I wear this wig to keep my head warm?
你以为我戴这头假发是为了保暖吗
Jack's compass? What does Beckett want with that?
杰克的罗盘? Beckett要那东西干什么?
Does it matter? I'm to find Jack and convince him to return to Port Royal.
无关紧要 我要去找到杰克 说服他回皇家港
In exchange, the charges against us will be dropped.
这样对我们的起诉就能撤销
No. We must find our own avenue to secure your freedom.
不 你们能否获得自由 不能操于他人之手
Is that a lack of faith in Jack or in me?
你是对杰克没信心 还是对我没信心?
That you would risk your life to save Sparrow
你愿意牺牲自己的性命去救斯派洛
does not mean he would do the same for anyone else.
不意味着他愿意为其他人做同样的事
Now, where is that dog with the keys?
那条有钥匙的狗跑哪去了?
I have faith in you.
我对你们有信心
Both of you.
你们两个
Where will you find him?
你到哪去找他?
Tortuga. I'll start there and I won't stop searching till I find him.
从龟岛找起 不找到他就不罢休
And then I intend to return here to marry you.
然后我会回来这里娶你
Properly? Eagerly, if you'll still have me.
正式的? 明媒正娶 如果你还要我的话
If it weren't for these bars, I'd have you already.
如果不是这铁栏杆 我早就是你的人了
I'll wait for you. Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
我会等你的 盯着海平线吧
Captain Jack Sparrow?
杰克・斯派洛船长?
Owes me four doubloons. Heard he was dead.
欠我4个金币 听说他死了
Singapore. That's what I heard. Drunk, with a smile on his face.
我听说在新加坡 喝醉了 当时他脸上还带着笑
Sure as the tide, Jack Sparrow turn up in Singapore.
确信 杰克・斯派洛在新加坡出现了
Jack Sparrow?
杰克・斯派洛
I haven't seen him in a month.
我一个月没见他了
When you find him, will you give him a message?
等你找到他 帮我带个口信给他好吗?
Can't say about Jack Sparrow,
杰克的事我说不好
but there's an island just south of the straits
但离海峡南面不远处有个小岛
where I trade spice for
我在那里用香料换…
delicious long pork.
喷香的羊肉
Cannot say about Jack, but you'll find a ship there.
杰克我说不好 但你能在那找到一条船
A ship with black sails.
一条挂黑帆的船
My brother will take you ashore.
我叫人带你上岸
What's wrong? The beach is there. C'est trop dangereux.
有什么问题吗?那儿就是海滩了 (法语)
What? C'est trop dangereux. Je vous I'avais dit.
什么? (法语)
Bon voyage. Monsieur.
(法语)再见 先生
Jack!
杰克
Jack Sparrow!
杰克・斯派洛
Marty!
马蒂
Cotton!
科顿
Anybody?
有人吗?
A familiar face.
熟面孔
Don't eat me.
别吃我
I'm not going to eat you. Don't eat me.
我不会吃你的 别吃我
No. Don't eat me.
不 别吃我
Gibbs.
吉布斯
Come on! Let's go!
我们走
Come on! Who wants it?
来啊  谁想来?
I can do this all day!
我整天都可以战斗
Jack?
杰克
Jack Sparrow!
杰克・斯派洛
I can honestly say I'm glad to see you.
能见到你我真是太高兴了
Jack, it's me.
杰克 是我啊
Will Turner.
威尔・特纳
Tell them to let me down!
让他们把我放下
...eensy-weensy.
...eunuchy. Snip, snip.
Eunuchy.
Jack, the compass. That's all I need.
杰克 那个罗盘 我只要那个
Elizabeth is in danger. We were arrested for helping you.
伊丽莎白有危险 我们因为帮你被捕了
She faces the gallows!
她会上绞架的
Savvy?
是吗?
Save me.
救我
Jack, what did you tell them?
杰克 你对他们说什么了
No!
不
What about Elizabeth?
伊丽莎白怎么办?
Jack!
杰克
That's a good girl. Come a little closer.
那是个好女孩 走进来些
We don't bite. Go on. We won't bite you.
我们不咬 过来 我们不咬你
Come quickly.
快点
Tell me what's happening. Our name still has some standing.
告诉我发生什么了? 我们还有一点名气
I've arranged passage to England. The captain is a friend of mine.
我安排你去英格兰 船长是我的朋友
No! Will's gone to find Jack!
不 威尔会找到杰克的
We cannot count on William Turner.
我们不能指望威廉・特纳
Come! He's better than you give him credit for.
快点 他比你想像的要强得多
This is no time for innocence. Beckett has offered one pardon only -
现在没时间讨论他 贝克特只愿意赦免一个人
one, and that is promised to Jack Sparrow.
那是对杰克・斯派洛的承诺
Even if Will succeeds,
即使威尔成功了
do not ask me to endure the sight of my daughter walking to the gallows. Do not.
你也不能让我 亲眼看我的女儿去送死
Perhaps I can ensure a fair trial for Will if he returns.
也许 等威尔回来的时候 我可以保证对他进行公平的审判
A fair trial for Will ends in a hanging. Then there is nothing left for you here.
对他的公平审判就是要吊死他 到时 你就没什么你牵挂的了
Wait inside.
在里面等
Captain?
船长?
Captain.
船长
Evening, Governor.
晚上好 总督大人
Shame, that.
可惜啊
He was carrying this.
他随身带着这个
It's a letter to the king.
一封给国王的信
It's from you. No...
你写的 不是
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎白
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
Where is she? Who?
她在哪? 谁?
No doubt you've discovered that loyalty is no longer the currency of the realm,
看来你已经意识到忠诚没什么用了
as your father believes.
不像你父亲那个死脑筋
Then what is?
那什么才有用呢?
I'm afraid currency is the currency of the realm.
恐怕只有金钱才能通行无阻
I expect, then, we can come to some sort of understanding.
我想这样我们应该能达成某种共识
I'm here to negotiate. I'm listening.
我是来谈判的 我在听
I'm listening intently.
我在仔细地听
These letters of marque are signed by the king.
这些私掠许可是国王签署的
Yes, and they're not valid until they bear my signature and my seal.
是的 不过没有我签字盖章 它们就不生效
Or else I would not still be here.
不然我也不会还待在这里了
You sent Will to get you the compass owned by Jack Sparrow.
你派威尔去找杰克・斯派洛要罗盘
It will do you no good. Do explain.
这对你不会有好处 请解释一下
I have been to the Isla de Muerta. I have seen the treasure myself.
我去过死亡之岛 我亲眼见过那些财宝
There is something you need to know. I see.
有些东西你需要了解 我懂了
You think the compass leads only to the Isla de Muerta
你以为那罗盘只是指向死亡之岛
and so you hope to save me from an evil fate.
所以你希望能挽救我免遭厄运困扰
But you mustn't worry.
但你不用担心
I care not for cursed Aztec gold.
我不想要那受诅咒的阿兹特克黄金
My desires are not so provincial.
我的眼光没有那么短浅
There's more than one chest of value in these waters.
在这片水域中 值钱的箱子不只一个
So perhaps you may wish to enhance your offer.
所以我认为你应该提高出价
Consider into your calculations that you robbed me of my wedding night.
计算的时候别忘了 你还搅了我的新婚之夜
So I did.
这倒是没错
A marriage interrupted
婚礼横遭打断
or fate intervenes?
是否天意如此呢?
You're making great efforts to ensure Jack Sparrow's freedom.
我们在尽力确保杰克・斯派洛的自由
These aren't going to Jack. Really?
这不仅仅是为了杰克 是吗?
To ensure Mr Turner's freedom, then,
要想确保特纳先生的自由
I'll still want that compass.
我还是要那个罗盘
Consider that in your calculations.
计算的时候别忘了这点
I say it was Divine Providence what escaped us from jail.
我觉得能从监狱逃走 是上帝保佑的结果
And I say it was me being clever.
我觉得幸亏是我比较聪明
Ain't that right, poochie?
对不对 普奇?
Well, how'd you know it weren't Divine Providence what inspired you to be clever?
你怎么知道你的小聪明 就不是上帝保佑的结果?
Anyways, I ain't stealing no ship.
不管怎样 我再不偷别人的船了
It ain't stealing. It's salvaging. And since when did you care?
那不是偷 是救援 什么时候你开始在意这个了?
Since we're not immortal no more. We gotta take care of our immortal souls.
自从我们不再是不死之身 我们得考虑一下世俗的灵魂了
You know you can't read. It's the Bible. You get credit for trying.
你知道你也看不懂 这可是圣经 试着读也会有奖励的
Pretending to read the Bible's a lie. That's a mark against...
装作在读圣经是一种谎言 这种行为会触怒…
Look.
看啊
There it is.
它在那
What's got into him?
它倒底怎么了?
Must have seen a catfish.
一定是见到鲶鱼了
Stupid mongrel!
蠢货
Come on!
来啊
It's ours for the taking. Tide's coming in. That should help.
这归我们啦 正巧涨潮了 大好时机啊
And salvaging is saving, in a manner of speaking.
从某种角度来说 救援船也是救赎啊
There's the truth of it!
没错
Suppose we better save it as soon as we can,
我看我们应该尽快"救赎"它
what with our souls in such a vulnerable state and all.
我们的肉体现在很脆弱
Amen to that.
阿门
Thank you.
谢谢
Why would he do this to us? If Jack is the chief...
他干嘛要这么对我们? 如果杰克是酋长的话?
Aye, the Pelegostos made Jack their chief,
土著们的确让杰克作了酋长
but he only remains chief as long as he acts like a chief.
只有酋长装得像样 他才能继续做下去
So he had no choice. He's a captive as much as the rest of us.
就是说他别无选择 他像我们其他人一样也不过是个囚犯
Worse, as it turns out. See, the Pelegostos believe that Jack is a god in human form,
事实上是更糟 土著认为杰克是附体的神灵
and they intend to do him the honour of releasing him from his fleshy prison.
他们想要把他 从现在的肉体中释放出来
They'll roast him and eat him.
他们会把他烤来吃了
Where's the rest of the crew?
其他船员哪里去了?
These cages we're in weren't built till after we got here.
关我们的这些笼子 是我们来了才造的
The feast is about to begin.
宴会就要开始了
Jack's life will end
鼓声一停
when the drums stop.
杰克就要没命了
Well, we can't just sit here and wait, then, can we?
那我们不能就待在这等着吧?
No, no. Oi! No, no.
不 不 不
More wood. Big fire. Big fire.
多弄点木头来 燃大火
I am Chief. Want big fire.
我是酋长 要燃大火
Come on.
快点
Tout de suite. Come on. More wood.
木头 快点 多弄点木头
Bugger.
糟糕
A little seasoning, eh?
得调调味 对吧
Well done.
干得不错
Put your legs through. Start to climb!
把腿伸出去 开始爬啊
Come on, men! It'll take all of us to crew the Black Pearl!
加油啊 驾驶"黑珍珠" 需要这里所有的人啊
Actually, you wouldn't need everyone.
其实不需要那么多人
About six would do.
有六个就足够了
Oh, dear.
哦 天啊
Hurry! Come on!
快啊 快啊
Come on! Is that all you got?
快点 你们就这么点本事?
Wait. Stop.
等等 停下来
Stop.
停下来
What are they doing? Stop.
他们在在做什么? 停下来
Snake!
有蛇
Move!
快走
Well, go on, go get them.
去啊 去抓住他们
No, no. Oi! No, no!
哦 不 不
Not good.
不妙
Cut it loose! Find a rock!
找石头把它切断
Roll the cage!
让笼子滚起来
Come on!
快点
Lift the cage! Hurry! Come on, lads. Lift it like a lady's skirt.
快点把笼子抬起来 快提起来 就像提女人的裙子一样
Run!
跑
This way, lads!
这边
Take cover!
小心
Stop it!
停手
Bugger.
糟糕
Haul loose the mooring line!
拉起驳船缆绳
The mooring line!
缆绳
Thief! Little hairy thief! Give it back!
小偷 毛头小偷 还给我
Don't bite it! Haul loose the mooring line!
不要咬 拉起驳船缆绳
He's got me eye. He won't give it back.
他拿走我的眼睛不还
How'd you get it back last time? Excellent! Our work's half done.
我们下次再拿回来 可以吗? 非常好 我们的工作完成一半了
We done it for you, knowing you'd be coming back.
我们都是为你做的 知道你会回来了
Make ready to sail, boys! What about Jack?
准备开船 伙计们 杰克呢?
I won't leave without him.
我不能丢下他
Time to go. Cast off those lines!
该走了 放下缆绳
Make ready to cast off!
放下缆绳
Good doggy.
乖狗狗
Alas, my children, this is the day you shall always remember as the day you almost...
你们应该永远记住今天
Captain Jack Sparrow.
你们差点捉到杰克・斯派洛船长
Let's get away from this island and head out to open sea.
我们赶快远离这座岛并航向大海吧
Yes to the first. Yes to the second, but only insofar as we keep to the shallows.
我同意 我同意 但我们不能离开浅滩太远
That seems a bit contradictory, Captain.
这似乎有点矛盾 船长
I have faith in your reconciliatory navigational skills.
我对你的"和解式"导航法相当有信心
Now, where is that monkey? I want to shoot something.
那只猴子跑哪去了 我想找它练靶子
Jack. Elizabeth is in danger.
杰克 伊莉莎白有危险
Have you considered just locking her up somewhere?
你有没有考虑过把她关起来
She is locked up, bound to hang for helping you.
她为了你现在被捉起来 即将被吊死
There comes a time when one must take responsibility for one's mistakes.
有时候人必须为了自己做错的事负责的
I need that compass of yours, Jack.
我需要你的罗盘 杰克
I must trade it for her freedom.
我要拿它去换取她的自由
Mr Gibbs. Captain.
吉布斯 船长
We have a need to travel upriver.
我们需要沿河逆流而上
By need, do you mean a trifling need?
你的"需要"是否只是你 一时兴起想到的小小愿望呢?
Fleeting? As in, say, a passing fancy?
不 我指的是很肯定
No, a resolute and unyielding need.
是不可更改的"需要"
What we need to do is make sail for Port Royal with all haste.
我们现在需要的是即刻回到皇家港
William,
威廉
I shall trade you the compass
我可以把罗盘给你
if you will help me
如果你帮我
to find this.
帮我找到这个的话
You want me to find this? No.
你要我帮你找这个? 不
You want you to find this,
是你自己想要找这个
because the finding of this finds you incapacitorially finding
因为找到这个的话
and/or locating in your discovering a way to save your dolly belle, ol' what's-her-face.
你便会在无尽的探索中发现到 解救你那位小甜心的方法
Savvy?
知道吗?
This is going to save Elizabeth?
这个东西可以解救伊莉莎白
How much do you know about Davy Jones?
你对戴维・琼斯了解多少?
Not much.
不多
Yeah, it's going to save Elizabeth.
没错 这东西可以救伊莉莎白
What's all this?
是这样的吗?
If you both fancy the dress, you'll just have to share and wear it one after the other.
你们都那么喜欢那件洋装的话 就轮流穿
It's not like that, sir. This ship is haunted.
不是这样的 船长 这艘船闹鬼了
Is it, now? And you?
是吗?你说
There's a female presence amongst us here, sir.
这船上有个女鬼 先生
All the men, they can feel it.
所有人都感觉到了
It's the ghost of a lady widowed before her marriage, I figure it,
我想是一位还未结婚便成了寡妇的女
searching for her husband, lost at sea.
来这船上找她死在海上的丈夫了
A virgin too, likely as not.
她还是个处女 可能也不是
And that bodes ill by all accounts.
这是厄运之兆
I say that we throw the dress overboard and we hope the spirit follows it.
我建议我们把这衣服丢下海 祈祷女鬼会跟着一起走
No! That will just anger the spirit, sir.
不行 那只会激怒她
What we need to do is find out what the spirit needs, and then get it back to her.
我们应搞清楚她想要什么 助她达成愿望
Enough! Enough!
够了 够了
You're a pair of superstitious goats and it's got the best of you.
你们已经迷信到昏头了
Now, this appears to be no more as we have a stowaway on board.
由这看来我们船上来了一位不速之客
A young woman, by the look of it.
一个年轻女人
I want you to search the ship and find her.
我要你们搜索全船把她找出来
Oh, and she's probably naked.
对了 她大概是一丝不挂的
Why is Jack afraid of the open ocean?
为何杰克这么怕大海?
Well, if you believe such things,
嗯 有这么一个传说
there's a beast does the bidding of Davy Jones -
戴维・琼斯的手下有一只怪兽
a fearsome creature with giant tentacles that'll suction your face clean off
它有着巨大的触手 一下就能把你的脸给吸下来
and drag an entire ship down to the crushing darkness.
然后把整艘船拉进海底深渊
The kraken.
挪威海怪
They say the stench of its breath is like...
就连它的呼吸…
Imagine, the last thing you know on God's green earth
想像你临死之前听到的…
is the roar of the kraken and the reeking odour of a thousand rotting corpses.
是它震耳欲聋的咆哮 闻到的是它腐尸般恶臭的呼吸
If you believe such things.
如果你相信这传说的话
And the key will spare him that?
钥匙可以帮他解脱吗?
Well, that's the very question Jack wants answered.
那正是杰克想知道的
Bad enough even to go visit
甚至不惜去问"她"
her.
"她"
Her?
她?
Aye.
对
No worries, mates. Tia Dalma and I go way back.
别担心 兄弟们 我跟蒂亚会回来的
Thick as thieves. Nigh inseparable, we are.
我们是如此地分不开
Were. Have been.
曾经
Before.
以前
I'll watch your back. It's me front I'm worried about.
我会帮你提防后面 我怕的是她从正面来
Mind the boat. Mind the boat.
看好船 看好船
Mind the boat.
看好船
Jack Sparrow.
杰克・斯派洛
Tia Dalma.
提亚・朵玛
I always knew the wind was going to blow you back to me one day.
我就知道总有一天风会把你吹回来
You...
你…
You have a touch of destiny about you, William Turner.
你对你的命运有预感 威廉・特纳
You know me?
你认识我?
You want to know me.
你想认识我
There'll be no knowing here. We've come for help and we're not leaving without it.
我们有求而来 不达目的是不会走的
I thought I knew you. Not so well as I had hoped.
我以为我已经认识你 似乎不如我预期的那样
Come. Come.
来 来
What service may I do you?
我能怎样为你效劳?
You know I demand payment. I brought payment.
你知道我需要报酬的 我带了报酬来
Look.
瞧
An undead monkey.
不死猴
Top that.
搁在上面了
Don't! You've no idea how long it took us to catch that.
不要 你不知道我们花了多久才抓到它的
The payment is fair.
这个报酬很合理
We're looking for this.
我们在找这个东西
And what it goes to.
还有它所开启的东西
The compass you bartered from me, it cannot lead you to this?
你之前从我这里得到的罗盘 无法帮你找到这钥匙的所在吗?
Maybe. Why?
也许可以 为什么?
Jack Sparrow does not know what he wants.
杰克・斯派洛也不知道自己在找什么
Or do you know,
或者你知道
but are loath to claim it as your own?
却不愿自己承认 是吗?
Your key go to a chest.
这把钥匙可以开启一个宝箱
And it is what lay inside the chest you seek, don't it?
宝箱里的东西才是你们在寻找的 对吧?
What is inside? Gold?
里面到底是什么 金子?
Jewels? Unclaimed properties of a valuable nature?
珠宝?或无人认领的贵重物品?
Nothing bad, I hope?
我希望 不是什么坏东西吧?
You know of Davy Jones,
你们知道戴维・琼斯吗?
yes?
什么?
A man of the sea.
他是个海员
A great sailor,
一个很棒的水手
until he run afoul of that which vex all men.
直到他碰上了一个 让任何男人都苦恼的东西
What vexes all men?
什么让任何男人都苦恼?
What indeed?
到底是什么东西?
The sea. Sums.
大海 宝物
The dichotomy of good and evil.
正义与邪恶的集合
A woman.
女人
He fell in love.
一个他爱上的女人
No, no, no, no. I heard it was the sea he fell in love with.
等等 我听说的是他爱上了大海
Same story, different versions, and all are true.
同样的故事 不同的版本 不过都是正确的
See, it was a woman
他爱上的那个女人
as changing and harsh
就如同大海般易变、残酷
and untamable as the sea.
无法驯服
Him never stopped loving her.
他从没停止爱她
But the pain it cause him was too much to live with
可是这样的爱为他带来了极大痛苦
but not enough to cause him to die.
却又不至于痛到取走他的生命
What exactly did he put into the chest?
他到底把什么放在宝箱里?
Him heart.
他的心
Literally or figuratively?
你是认真的还是在比喻?
He couldn't literally put his heart in a chest.
他怎么可能真的把他的心放在宝箱里
Could he?
可能吗?
It was not worth feeling what small, fleeting joy life brings.
他觉得爱得这么痛苦太不值得了
And so
于是
him carve out him heart,
他挖出了他的心
lock it away in a chest and hide the chest from the world.
将它锁进了宝箱 再把宝箱藏了起来
The key
这把钥匙
he keep with him at all times.
他寸步不离地带在身边
You knew this. I did not. I didn't know where the key was.
你早就知道了吧 我不知道 我原本不知道钥匙在哪里
But now we do. All that's left is to climb aboard the Flying Dutchman, grab the key,
现在剩下的就是去找到"飞行荷兰人" 拿了钥匙
you go back to Port Royal and save your bonnie lass, eh?
回到皇家港 救出你的甜心
Let me see your hand.
让我看看你的手
The black spot!
黑斑
The black spot! Black spot!
黑斑 黑斑
My eyesight's as good as ever, just so you know.
我的视力还是跟以前一样好
I have just the thing. Now, where did I put it?
我有样东西 我把它放哪儿了?
My little beauty, where are you?
我的小美丽 你在哪里
Such a long time in such a mess.
这么长时间的混乱
Davy Jones cannot make port.
戴维・琼斯不能上岸
Cannot step on land but once every ten years.
不能上岸 他每十年才能踏上土地一次
Land is where you are safe, Jack Sparrow,
在地上你才是安全的 杰克・斯派洛
and so you will carry land with you.
所以 你把土地带着
Dirt.
泥土
This is a jar of dirt. Yes.
这是一罐泥土 对
Is the jar of dirt going to help?
这罐泥土有用吗?
If you don't want it, give it back.
你不想要的话就还我
No. Then it helps.
不要 它会帮上忙的
It seems we have a need to find the Flying Dutchman.
我们需要找到"飞行荷兰人"
A touch of destiny.
预测命运
That's the Flying Dutchman?
那就是"飞行荷兰人"?
She doesn't look like much. Neither do you.
看起来不怎么样 你看起来也不怎么样
Do not underestimate her.
别小看她
Must have run afoul of the reef. So, what's your plan, then?
它看起来好像触礁了 你打算怎么办?
I row over, search the ship until I find your bloody key.
我划小船过去 翻遍整艘船 直到找到你的钥匙为止
And if there are crewmen?
如果有船员呢?
I cut down anyone in my path.
谁挡路我就砍谁
I like it. Simple, easy to remember.
很好 我喜欢 简单明了
Your chariot awaits you, Sire.
先生 你的战车等着你呢
If you do happen to get captured, just say Jack Sparrow sent you to settle his debt.
如果你被逮住了 就说 杰克・斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
It might save your life. Bon voyage!
它能让你活命 祝你好运
Douse the lamps.
熄灯
Sailor.
水手
Hoisting the jib, Captain's orders. Sailor!
船长命令 扬帆 水手
Hoisting the jib. Bring up with a round turn.
扬起帆 掉头
There's no use. You've run aground.
没有用 我们搁浅了
No.
不
Beneath us.
在我们下面
Foul breath.
有可怕的呼吸声
Down on your marrowbones and pray.
求饶祈祷吧
Get back! Get back!
退开 退开
Five men still alive. The rest have moved on.
只剩五人活着 其他的都死了
Do you fear death?
你怕死吗?
Do you fear that dark abyss?
你畏惧那黑色深渊吗?
All your deeds laid bare.
你的一生尽现于此
All your sins punished.
你的罪行将被惩罚
I can offer you an escape. Don't listen to him!
我可以给你逃命的机会 别听他胡说
Do you not fear death?
你不怕死亡吗?
I'll take my chances, sir.
我宁可冒这个险
To the depths.
丢下海
Cruel blackguard!
可恶
Life is cruel.
生命是残酷的
Why should the afterlife be any different?
死后的世界难道有什么不同吗?
I offer you a choice.
我给你一个机会
Join my crew
加入我的团队
and postpone the judgment.
推迟你的审判
One hundred years before the mast.
你可以多活一百年
Will ye serve?
你愿意加入吗?
I will serve.
我愿意
You are neither dead nor dying.
你没死 也不会死
What is your purpose here?
你为何来这里?
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
杰克・斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
What is your purpose here?
你为何来这里?
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
杰克・斯派洛派我来处理他的债务
Did he, now?
是吗?
I'm sorely tempted to accept that offer.
真是个让人心动的提议
You have a debt to pay.
你要还债
You've been captain of the Black Pearl for 13 years.
你做了"黑珍珠"的船长十三年
That was our agreement.
那是我们约好的
Technically I was only captain for two years, then I was mutinied upon.
确来说我只做了两年 然后就被推翻了
Then you were a poor captain, but a captain nonetheless.
你是个可怜的船长 但你还是船长
Have you not introduced yourself all these years as Captain Jack Sparrow?
这些年来你每次自我介绍时 不都自称"杰克・斯派洛船长"吗?
You have my payment. One soul to serve on your ship.
我已经赔付了给你 我已经送了个人给你当水手
One soul is not equal to another.
两个灵魂不能混为一谈
We've established my proposal is sound in principle. Now we're haggling over price.
我们已经达成了共识 接下来我们谈谈价钱吧
Price?
价钱?
Just how many souls do you think my soul is worth?
我的灵魂需要多少人来换
One hundred souls.
一百人的灵魂
Three days.
三天时间
You're a diamond, mate. Send me back the boy. I'll get started right off.
你真是个宝 伙计 你把那孩子送回来我们马上去办
I keep the boy. A good-faith payment.
我要把这孩子留做保证金
That leaves you only 99 more to go.
再给我99人就好了
Have you not met Will Turner?
你没有遇见威尔・特纳吗?
He's noble, heroic, a terrific soprano.
他正直、英勇 还是个娘娘腔
Worth at least four.
至少可抵四个
Maybe three and a half.
也许三个半人
And did I happen to mention
我有没有提到过?
he's in love?
他正在热恋中
With a girl.
和一个女孩
Due to be married.
即将要成婚
Betrothed.
已经订婚了
Dividing him from her and her from him would only be half as cruel as actually allowing them to be joined in holy matrimony. Eh?
硬生生把他和他的爱人拆散 不会比让他们成婚还更残酷吧?
I keep the boy. 99 souls.
我要留着他 你再给我99个人
But I wonder, Sparrow,
我在想 斯派洛
can you live with this?
你良心能安稳吗?
Can you condemn an innocent man, a friend,
你能宣判一个无辜的人 一个朋友
to a lifetime of servitude in your name while you roam free?
宣判他无期徒刑 而你自己却在享受自由吗?
Yep. I'm good with it.
是的 我没有问题
Shall we seal it in blood? I mean ink.
我们需要滴血…墨为盟吗?
Three days.
三天时间
Mr Gibbs. Aye.
吉布斯 是的
I feel sullied and unusual.
我突然觉得跟平常不同
And how do you intend to harvest these 99 souls in three days?
你打算怎么在三天内找到99人?
Fortunately, he was mum as to the condition in which these souls need be.
幸运的是 他并没有提及他要的是什么样的人
Tortuga.
龟岛
It's an outrage. Port tariffs, berthing fees,
这简直是侮辱 港口税 船棚费
wharf handling and, heaven help us, pilotage.
处理费 上帝啊 还有导航费
Are we all to work for the East India Trading Company, then?
我们真的得为东印度公司工作吗?
I'm afraid, sir, Tortuga is the only free port left in these waters.
船长 现在完全免费的港口只剩龟岛了
A pirate port is what you mean. Well, I'm sorry.
你是指那个海盗港 嗯 抱歉
An honest sailor is what I am. I make my living fair and I sleep well each night.
我是个诚实的航海员 我做的是正当的生意 晚上我睡觉才安稳
Sir!
船长
She wants you to do something.
她想叫你做什么
She's trying to give a sign.
她好像在给我们什么暗示
Over there! Look for a sign!
那边 找找看有什么暗示
Look, there! There it is!
在那边 找到了
There's the sign! That's seaweed.
她给的暗示 那是海草
Seaweed can be a sign. Looks like entrails.
海草也可以是个暗示吧 我看像是什么生物的内脏
That would be a bad sign. What's that over there?
那是不好的预兆 那是什么东西?
"龟岛"
And what makes you think you're worthy to crew the Black Pearl?
你为何认为自己 可以成为"黑珍珠"的一员呢?
I've never sailed a day in me life.
我从来没有乘过船
I figure I should get out, see the world while I'm still young.
我只是想趁还年轻时多看看世界
You'll do. Make your mark. Next!
非常好 请签字 下一个
My wife ran off with my dog
我太太带着我的狗 跟人跑了
and I'm drunk for a month
我已经醉了一个月
and I don't give an ass rat's if I live or die.
现在的我对自己是死是活 已经不在乎了
Perfect. Next! I knowwhat I want. I knowwhat I want...
非常好 下一位 我知道我需要什么
Me have one arm and a bum leg. It's the crow's nest for you.
我只有一只手 且脚是跛的 这是给你乌鸦巢
I knowwhat I want. Next!
我知道我要的是什么 下一位
Ever since I was a little lad, I've always wanted to sail the seas forever.
我从小就想当个水手
Sooner than you think. Sign the roster.
你的梦想就快实现了 请签字
Thanks very much.
多谢
How we going? Including those four, that gives us four.
招到几个了? 包括刚才那四个 一共四个
And what's your story?
你又有什么故事?
My story.
我的故事
It's exactly the same as your story, just one chapter behind.
我的故事就和你的故事一样 只不过慢你一章
I chased a man across the seven seas.
我为了追缉一个人 航遍了七海
The pursuit cost me my crew,
这漫长的追赶 使得我失去了我的船员
my commission,
我的军衔
and my life.
以及我的生命
Commodore? No, not any more. Weren't you listening?
司令官? 我已经不是司令官了 你没听到我说的话吗?
I nearly had you all off Tripoli.
在的黎波里 我差点就捉到你们了
I would have, if not for the hurricane.
如果不是因为那该死的飓风的话
Lord.
天啊
You didn't try to sail through it?
你不会是硬闯飓风吧?
So, do I make your crew or not?
我到底能不能加入你们?
You haven't said where you're going.
你还没说你们要去哪里
Somewhere nice?!
是个好地方吗?
So, am I worthy to serve
我到底有没有这荣幸
under Captain Jack Sparrow?
为杰克・斯派洛船长效劳?
Or should I just kill you now?
或是我现在就杀了你
You're hired.
你被录取了
Sorry. Old habits and all that.
对不起 老习惯改不了
Easy, sailor! That's our captain you're threatening.
小心 水手 你枪指的是船长
Time to go. Aye!
该走了 是
Thanks, mate.
谢了 兄弟
Carry on.
请继续
Come on, then! Who wants some?
来啊 你们谁想挨揍?
Form an orderly line and I'll have you all, one by one.
排成一列 我会一个个收拾你们
Come on, who's first?
来来来 谁先来?
I just wanted the pleasure of doing that myself.
我只是想享受打昏他的乐趣
James Norrington.
詹姆士・诺灵顿
What has the world done to you?
这世界对你做了什么?
Heave!
拉起来
Heave! Heave!
拉起来 拉起来
Secure the mast tackle, Mr Turner!
稳固桅杆 特纳
Set to it!
栓紧它
Step aside. Hey! Mind yourself!
让开 嘿 管好你自己
Let go, boy!
走开
No.
不
Haul that weevil to his feet.
把他绑起来
Five lashes will remind you to stay on 'em!
赏你五鞭让你知道怎么服从命令
No! Lmpeding me in my duties?
不要 居然敢违抗我的命令?
You'll share the punishment. I'll take it all.
你们都要受罚 罚我一个人就好
Will you, now?
你一个人?
And what would prompt such an act of charity?
什么时候你变得这么有同情心?
My son.
我的儿子
He's my son.
他是我的儿子
What fortuitous circumstance be this?
真的好巧呀
Five lashes be owed, I believe it is.
你代替我来赏他五鞭吧
No. No, I won't!
不 我不行
The cat's out of the bag, Mr Turner.
特纳先生 只要在他背上快快抽五下
Your issue will feel its sting, be it by the bosun's hand or your own.
你打他会比我或其它人打的更不疼吧
No.
不
Bosun! No!
布舍尔！不要！
You had it easy, boy!
便宜你了 小子
Will. I don't need your help.
威尔 我不需要你的帮忙
The bosun prides himself on cleaving flesh from bone, with every swing.
要不是我 你一定被打得皮开肉绽
So I'm to understand what you did was an act of compassion?
这么说来你打我都是为了我好
Yes.
是的
100 years before the mast, losing who you were, bit by bit,
在你服役的这一百年 你的肉体会渐渐剥落
until you end up... end up like poor Wyvern here.
直到你像可怜的威尔一样
Once you've sworn an oath to the Dutchman, there's no leaving it.
一旦你宣誓为"飞行荷兰人"效忠后 这就是你必得的下场
Not until your debt is paid.
直到债务偿还
I've sworn no oath.
我并没有宣誓
You must get away.
你得离开
Not until I find this.
那你应该快点离开
The key.
钥匙
The dead man's chest.
亡灵箱之钥
What do you know of this?
你知道些什么?
Open the chest with the key, and stab the heart...
用那把钥匙打开宝箱 再一刀剌进那心脏
No, don't stab the heart.
不不不 不能剌那心脏
The Dutchman needs a living heart or there'll be no captain,
"飞行荷兰人"需要一个活的心脏 心脏死的话船长就死了
and if there's no captain, there's no one to have the key.
船长死了的话就没人有钥匙了
So the captain has the key?
这么说钥匙在船长身上?
Where is the key? Hidden.
钥匙在哪里? 藏起来了
Where is the chest? Hidden.
宝箱又在哪里? 藏起来了
Captain Sparrow!
斯派洛船长
Come to join me crew, lad? Welcome aboard.
来加入我的船队吗? 欢迎
I'm here to find the man I love.
我是来找我心爱的男人的
I'm deeply flattered, son, but my first and only love is the sea.
我深感荣幸 可惜大海是我最爱 也是唯一的爱
Meaning William Turner, Captain Sparrow.
我是指威廉・特纳 斯派洛船长
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎白
Hide the rum.
把朗姆酒藏起来
These clothes do not flatter you. It should be a dress or nothing.
这套衣服一点都不适合你 要么穿女装 要么什么都不穿
I happen to have no dress in my cabin. Jack.
刚好我的舱房里一件女装都没有 杰克
I know Will came to find you. Where is he?
我知道威尔来找过你 他在哪里
Darling, I am truly unhappy to have to tell you this, but
亲爱的 我实在很不愿意告诉你
through unfortunate circumstances that had nothing whatsoever to do with me,
在一连串与我无关也无法预料的不幸事件中
poor Will has been press-ganged into Davy Jones's crew.
可怜的威尔被戴维・琼斯抓去当水手了
Davy Jones?
戴维・琼斯?
Oh, please.
拜托
The captain of the Flying Dutchman?
就是"飞行荷兰人"的船长
You look awful. What are you doing here? You hired me.
瞧你副德行 来我船上干吗? 是你雇我来的
I can't help it if your standards are lax.
你雇佣标准这么低 这我也无能为力
You smell funny. Jack!
你臭死了 杰克
All I want is to find Will.
我只想找到威尔
Are you certain? Is that what you really want most?
你确信? 真的很想找到他?
Of course.
是的
Because I would think you'd want to find a way to save Will most.
依我看你应该找的是 一个解救威尔的办法
And you'd have a way of doing that? Well,
你有办法是吗? 是这样…
there is a chest. Oh, dear.
有那么一个宝箱 哦 亲爱的
A chest of unknown size and origin.
它大小不知 地点不明
What contains the still-beating heart of Davy Jones.
里面装的是 戴维・琼斯那颗仍然跳动的心
And whoever possesses that chest
只要拥有这宝箱
possesses the leverage to command Jones to do whatever it is he or she wants,
就能命令琼斯做任何事
including saving brave William from his grim fate.
包括从困境中解救勇敢的威尔
You don't actually believe him, do you?
你不会真的相信他这一套吧?
Howwould we find it?
怎么才能找到它呢?
With this.
用这个
My compass is unique.
我这罗盘世上独一无二
"Unique" here having the meaning of "broken".
独一无二? 你是说它失灵了吧?
True enough, this compass does not point north.
没错 这个罗盘不会指向北
Where does it point?
那它指向哪?
It points to the thing you want most in this world.
它会指向这世上你最想要的东西
Jack.
哦 杰克
Are you telling the truth? Every word, love.
这是真的吗? 句句属实 亲爱的
And what you want most in this world
这世上你最想要的就是…
is to find the chest of Davy Jones, is it not?
戴维・琼斯的亡灵箱 是吗?
To save Will. By finding the chest of Davy Jones.
去救威尔 先找到戴维・琼斯的亡灵箱
Mr Gibbs! Cap'n.
吉布斯先生 船长
We have our heading. Finally!
有航向了 终于有了
Cast off those lines. Weigh anchor and crowd that canvas!
割断缆绳 向罗盘指示的方向前进 起锚 扬帆
Miss Swann.
斯旺小姐
Welcome to the crew, former commodore.
欢迎加入我们的队伍 前司令官
There's something to knowing the exact shape of the world and one's place in it.
我们得通晓世界地理
I assure you, these are not necessary.
我向你保证 这些完全没有必要
I thought you'd be interested in the whereabouts of your daughter.
我以为你关心你女儿的下落
You have news of her? Most recently seen on Tortuga,
你有她的消息吗? 不久前在龟岛上出现过
and then left in the company of a known pirate, Jack Sparrow,
后来上了海盗杰克・斯派洛的贼船
and other fugitives from justice.
这船上聚集的都是些法外之徒
"Justice"? Hardly.
法！哪里还有王法！
Including the previous owner of this sword, I believe.
其中还包括这把剑的主人
Our ships are in pursuit. Justice will be dispensed by cannonade and cutlass,
我已经派出船只 正义将被重新伸张
and all manner of remorseless pieces of metal.
到时候剑拔弩张 枪炮无眼
I find it distasteful to even contemplate the horror facing all those on board.
依我看 那贼船上的人恐怕性命难保
What do you want from me?
你想从我这里得到什么?
Your authority as governor, your influence in London,
你的地方管辖权 加上你在伦敦的影响力
and your loyalty to the East India Trading Company.
并且要你效忠于东印度公司
To you, you mean.
是效忠于你吧?
Shall I remove these shackles?
要我帮你打开手铐吗?
Do what you can for my daughter.
尽可能地帮我找女儿
So you see, Mercer, every man has a price he will willingly accept.
你看 只要价位合适 几乎任何人都可以被收买
Even for what he hoped never to sell.
哪怕是他从不曾打算出卖的东西
I wager ten years.
我赌十年
I'll match ten years.
跟你 我也赌十年
Agreed.
好吧
Wondering how it's played?
你知道怎么玩么?
I understand. Liar!
知道 开!
It's a game of deception. But your bet includes all the dice, not just your own.
这是一场欺诈的赌博 你赌所有骰子的点数 不光是自己的
What are they wagering? The only thing we have.
赌注是什么? 我们唯一拥有的东西
Years of service.
在船上服侍的年份
So any crew member can be challenged? Aye. Anyone.
跟谁都可以对赌? 是的 都可以
I challenge Davy Jones.
我要和戴维・琼斯赌
I accept, mate.
我接受了
The stakes? My soul. An eternity of servitude.
你的赌注呢? 我的灵魂 永远的被奴役
No!
不！
Against?
你想赢什么?
I want this.
我要这个
How do you know of the key? That's not part of the game, is it?
你是怎么知道这钥匙的? 这与赌局无关 不是吗?
You can still walk away.
你现在放弃还不迟
What's this? I'm in. Matching his wager.
这算什么? 我也要赌 和他的赌注一样
No! Don't do this.
不！别这样
The die is cast.
游戏已经开始了
I bid three twos.
我猜3个二
It's your bid, Captain.
该你了 船长
Four fours.
4个四
Four fives.
4个五
Six threes.
6个三
Seven fives.
7个五
Eight fives.
8个五
Welcome to the crew, lad.
欢迎入队 年青人
Twelve fives.
12个五
Call me a liar, or up the bid.
叫我开 要不就继续加
And be called a liar myself for my trouble?
想让我放弃 承认自己输了?
Bootstrap Bill, you're a liar and you will spend an eternity on this ship.
鞋带比尔 你输了 今生今世都要呆在这船上
Master Turner, feel free to go ashore
特纳先生 想上岸的话随你
the very next time we make port!
不过要等到我们下次靠岸喽！
Fool. Why did you do that?
你真傻 为什么要这么做?
I couldn't let you lose.
我不能让你输
It was never about winning or losing.
关键并不在于输赢
The key.
是钥匙
You just wanted to know where it was.
你只是想知道钥匙藏在哪儿
Captain says I'm to relieve you.
船长让我来换你的班
Captain's orders.
船长的命令
Here. Take this, too.
把这个也拿着
Now, get yourself to land, and stay there.
回到岸上去 不要再下海了
It was always in my blood to die at sea.
我命中注定要死在海上的
It was not a fate I ever wanted for you.
但我不希望你也有同样的命运
It's not a fate you had to choose for yourself, either.
你也可以不选择如此命运
Aye. I could say I did what I had to, when I left you to go pirating.
我当初是不得已 才抛弃你去当海盗的
But it would taste a lie to say it wasn't what I wanted.
但是对你说谎并不是我所想要的
You owe me nothing, Will.
威尔 你不欠我什么
Now go.
走吧
They'll know you helped me.
他们会知道是你帮了我
What more can they do to me?
他们还能把我怎么样呢?
I take this with a promise.
我以这把匕首向你保证
I'll find a way to sever Jones's hold on you,
我会把你从琼斯的魔爪中救出来
and not rest until this blade pierces his heart.
不用这匕首刺入他的心绝不罢休
I will not abandon you.
我永远不会抛弃你
I promise.
我发誓
Beckett? Yes, they're signed.
贝克特? 是的 他们都签字了
Lord Cutler Beckett of the East India Trading Company.
东印度公司的贝克特勋爵
Will was working for Beckett and never said a word.
威尔在为贝克特勋爵效劳！ 他可一个字也没提过
Beckett wants the compass. Only one reason for that.
贝克特想要你的罗盘 目的只有一个
Of course.
没错
He wants the chest. Yes, he did say something about a chest.
他想得到亡灵箱 没错 他的确提到过什么宝箱的
If the company controls the chest, they controls the sea.
如果东印度公司控制了亡灵箱 就等于控制了整个大海
A truly discomfiting notion, love. And bad.
大海将面临灾难 亲爱的 还有厄运
Bad for every mother's son what calls himself a pirate.
天下每个海盗的厄运
I think there's a bit more speed to be coaxed from these sails.
我们需要加快速度
Brace the foreyard!
升船头帆！
Might I enquire as to how you came by these?
你能告诉我是怎么得到这东西的吗?
Persuasion. Friendly?
说服力 是友好的那种么?
Decidedly not.
完全不是
Will strikes a deal, yet you were the one with the prize - full pardon.
威尔为了它煞费苦心 你却轻而易举就得到了－赦免令
"Commission as a privateer on behalf of England
"作为大英帝国授权的私掠船长
and the East India Trading Company."
替东印度公司服务
As if I could be bought for such a low price.
你以为这点东西就能收买我了
Jack, the letters, give them back. No.
那你把赦免令还给我 不行
Persuade me.
你得先说服我
You do know Will taught me how to handle a sword?
你知道威尔教过我如何用剑吗?
As I said, persuade me.
我说过了 要先说服我
It's a curious thing.
真是奇怪啊
There was a time I would have wanted you to look like that while thinking about me.
我曾经愿意舍弃一切 只想换来你对我动情一笑
I don't know what you mean. I think you do.
我不懂你的意思 我知道你懂
Don't be absurd. I trust him, that's all.
别瞎猜 我只是信任他而已
So you never wondered how your latest fiance
你那未婚夫怎么会无缘无故
ended up on the Flying Dutchman in the first place?
沦落到"飞行的荷兰人"上呢?
Strange to come upon a longboat so far out in open water.
公海上突然出现一艘救生艇
Just put as many leagues behind us as you can. As fast as you can.
你们最好开全速 越快越好
And what are we running from?
我们要逃避什么吗?
That dress. Where did you get it?
这套女装 哪儿来的?
It was found aboard the ship.
船上找到的
The crew thought it was a spirit bringing some omen of ill-fate.
船员们认为这是幽灵带来的 某种坏运气的征兆
That's foolish. Yes. Exceedingly foolish.
胡说八道 是啊 一派胡言
It brought good fortune. The spirit told us, "Pull in at Tortuga",
它可给我们带来了好运 幽灵告诉我们"去龟岛"
and we made a nice bit of profit there.
我们在那里挣了一大笔钱
Off the books, of course.
像魔术一样
I imagine some of your crew may have jumped ship there.
我猜你们船员中有人在龟岛离船了
Why do you ask? Captain! A ship's been spotted.
你为什么这么问? 船长！一艘船向我们驶来
Colours? She isn't flying any.
旗帜什么颜色? 没有旗帜
Pirates. Or worse.
是海盗 没错
You will watch this.
你给我挣大眼睛好好瞧着
Let no joyful voice be heard!
欢声笑语顿然不再
Let no man look up at the sky with hope.
仰天绝望尝尽悲哀
And let this day be cursed by we who ready to wake
今天让他们见识什么叫厉害
the kraken.
召唤挪威海怪
No!
不！
I've doomed us all.
我把这船人都害了
It's the Flying Dutchman!
是"飞行的荷兰人"
Mother Carey's chickens! What happened?
他妈的这是怎么了?
Must have hit a reef.
一定是触礁了
Free the rudder! Hard to port then hard to starboard.
松舵！左满舵然后右满舵
Free the rudder! Hard to port!
松舵！ 左满舵！
Kraken! Kraken!
挪威海怪！ 挪威海怪！
Here it is! Take it!
在这里！拿去吧！
Take it!
拿去吧！
The boy's not here. He must have been claimed by the sea.
没看到那小子 一定是被大海吞噬了
I am the sea.
我就是大海
You need time alone with your thoughts.
给你点时间哀悼
Brig! What of the survivors?
布羚！ 幸存者怎么办?
There are no survivors.
无一幸存
The chest is no longer safe. Chart a course to Isla Cruces.
亡灵箱已经不再安全了 向克鲁斯岛出发
Get me there first, or there'll be the devil to pay.
一定要先到达 不然有你们受的
"First"?
"先到达"?
Who sent that thieving charlatan onto my ship?
是谁把那小贼安排在我船上?
Who told him of the key?
是谁告诉他有关钥匙的事?
Jack Sparrow.
杰克・斯派洛
My intuitive sense of the female creature informs me that you are troubled.
我对女人的直觉告诉我你心情烦躁
I just thought I'd be married by now.
我只是在想我现在本该结婚了的
I'm so ready to be married.
我为结婚做了那么多的准备
You know...
你知道...
Lizzie, I am captain of a ship,
莉齐 我是船长
and being captain of a ship, I could in fact perform a "marr-i-age" right here.
作为一名船长 我必须完成"结啊婚"的任务
Right on this deck.
就在这甲板上
Right now.
立即完成
No, thank you.
不行 谢谢
Why not?
为什么不?
We are very much alike, you and I. I and you. Us.
我们是那么的相似 你和我 我和你
Except for a sense of honour and decency and a moral centre.
除了荣誉感 行为准则和道德体系
And personal hygiene.
还有个人卫生
Trifles.
都是小事
You will come over to my side. I know it.
你早晚会跟我当海盗的
You seem very certain. One word, love. Curiosity.
你好像很有把握 一个词 亲爱的 好奇心
You long for freedom.
你渴望自由
You long to do what you want to do because you want it.
渴望能做自己想做的事情 这是你的个性
To act on selfish impulse.
冲动而且执着
You want to see what it's like.
你想去亲身体验一下
One day, you won't be able to resist.
早晚有一天 你将无法抗拒
Why doesn't your compass work?
为什么你的罗盘失灵了?
My compass works fine.
我的罗盘工作得很好
Because you and I are alike,
因为你和我一样
and there will come a moment when you have a chance to show it.
都有善良的一面
To do the right thing. I love those moments.
它会找时机表现出来的 我很珍惜这种时机
I like to wave at them as they pass by.
每当这种时机降临时 我总会挥手相送
You'll have the chance to do something... something courageous.
你将有机会做勇敢正义之事
And when you do, you'll discover something.
到那时 你会发现
That you're a good man.
你原来是个好人
All evidence to the contrary.
所有证据显示 事实恰恰相反
I have faith in you.
我对你有信心
Want to know why? Do tell, dearie.
想知道为什么吗? 那就说吧 小宝贝
Curiosity.
好奇心
You're going to want it.
你渴望得到一个机会
A chance to be admired and gain the rewards that follow.
受人钦佩 得到嘉奖
You won't be able to resist.
你将无法抗拒
You're going to want to know what it tastes like.
你会想去亲身体验一下
I do want to knowwhat it tastes like.
我的确想亲身体验一下
But, seeing as you're a good man,
但是 身为一个好人
I know that you'd never put me in a position that would compromise my honour.
我知道你不会趁人之危
I'm proud of you, Jack.
我为你自豪 杰克
Land, ho!
陆地！
I want my jar of dirt.
我需要我那罐土
You're pulling too fast. You're pulling too slow.
你划的太快了 是你划的太慢了
We don't want the kraken to catch us. I'm saving me strength for when it comes.
我们都不想挪威海怪追上我们 我是在为紧急关头攒把力
And I don't think it's "kracken" anyways.
才不叫"挪威海兽"呢
I always heard it said "krayken".
我总是听人叫"挪威海王"
With a long a?
A发长音?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. "Krocken" is how it's pronounced in Scandinavian,
不 不 不 "挪威海王"是北欧那边的发音
and "kracken" is closer to that.
"挪威海兽"更接近一点
We ain't Scandinavians, are we? "Krayken."
我们可不在北欧 不是吗? "挪威海贼"
It's a mythological creature. I can calls it what I wants.
它不过是个神话中的动物 我想怎样称乎就怎样称乎
Guard the boat. Mind the tide.
把船看好 注意潮水
Don't touch my dirt.
别碰我那罐土
This doesn't work. And it certainly doesn't show you what you want most.
它坏了 根本就不能指向你想要的东西
Yes, it does. You're sitting on it.
当然能 你就坐在上面
Beg pardon? Move.
你说什么? 起来
"Guard the boat!" "Mind the tide!" I could join the circus.
"把船看好！""注意潮水！" 我要参加马戏团
Mind if I shine your shoes, sir?
要不要我给你擦鞋啊 先生?
They're here. And I cannot step foot on land again for near of a decade.
他们已经到了 我已经近十年不能上岸了
You'll trust us to act in your stead?
你相信我们能做好吧?
I'll trust you to know what awaits you should you fail!
我要你们相信如果失败会有什么后果！
Down, then! Down!
下潜 马上！ 下潜！
It's real.
是真的
You actually were telling the truth.
你还真说了句实话
I do that quite a lot, yet people are always surprised.
我说过很多实话 不知为什么当人们发现时总是会惊讶
With good reason!
这其中是有原因的
Will!
威尔！
You're all right! Thank God! I came to find you!
你没事！谢天谢地 我是来找你的！
How did you get here?
你怎么到这来的?
Sea turtles, mate. A pair of them, strapped to my feet.
我捉住一对海龟 绑在双脚上
Not so easy, is it?
游过来不容易 对吧?
But I do owe you thanks, Jack. You do?
不过我还得好好谢谢你 杰克 真的么?
After you tricked me onto that ship to square your debt with Jones...
即使是你先骗我上了戴维・琼斯的船 让我去还你的债
What? What?
什么? 什么?
...I was reunited with my father.
我才能和我父亲重聚
Well, you're welcome, then.
哦 不必客气
Everything you said to me, every word was a lie!
你对我说的每件事每个字都是谎言
Pretty much.
没错
Time and tide, love.
恶习难改 亲爱的
Oi! What are you doing?
哎！ 你想干什么?
I'm going to kill Jones.
我要杀了琼斯
Can't let you do that, William.
这可不行 威廉
Cos if Jones is dead, who's to call his terrible beastie off the hunt, eh?
如果琼斯死了 谁还能驾驭他那只怪兽?
Now, if you please.
现在 如果你不介意
The key.
把钥匙给我
I keep the promises I make, Jack.
我要兑现我的诺言 杰克
I intend to free my father. I hope you're here to see it.
我要还父亲的自由 我希望你能目睹一切
I can't let you do that either. So sorry.
我也不能让你那么做 很抱歉
I knew you'd warm up to me eventually.
我就知道你早晚会站在我这一边的
Lord Beckett desires the content of that chest.
贝克特勋爵渴望得到这箱子里的东西
I deliver it, I get my life back.
一旦给他带回去 我将重新拥有一切
The dark side of ambition.
阴险的野心
I prefer to see it as the promise of redemption.
我认为是赎罪的曙光
Stop it!
住手！
Will!
威尔！
Guard the chest! No!
看好箱子！ 不！
This is barbaric! This is no way for grown men to...
太野蛮了！ 没门儿...
Fine! Let's just haul out our swords and start banging away at each other.
好吧！我们都拔出剑来互相攻击
That will solve everything! I've had it!
这样能解决所有的事情！ 我受够了！
I've had it with wobbly-legged, rum-soaked pirates!
我受够了你们这些软脚虾  烂酒鬼 臭海盗
How'd this go all screwy? Well, each wants the chest for hisself.
这到底是怎么回事儿啊? 他们都想独吞箱子
Mr Norrington, I think, is trying to regain a bit of honour,
诺灵顿想拿回去立功赎罪
old Jack's looking to trade it, save his own skin,
杰克想还给琼斯 挽回面子
then Turner, there, I think he's trying to settle some unresolved business
特纳想兑现诺言
'twixt him and his twice-cursed pirate father.
拯救他变成水鬼的父亲
Sad. This is madness!
悲哀 真是疯子！
That chest must be worth more than a shiny penny.
那箱子一定价值不菲
Terrible temptation.
是祸根
If we was any kind of decent, we'd remove temptation from their path.
假如我们还有点良知 就应该为他们除去这罪魁祸首
Enough!
够了！
The heat!
太热了！
Bugger!
混蛋！
By your leave, Mr Turner.
抱歉了 特纳先生
By your leave, Mr Norrington.
抱歉了 诺灵顿先生
Do excuse me while I kill the man who ruined my life.
抱歉 我得先杀了这个毁了我一生幸福的人
Be my guest. Let us examine that claim for a moment.
请便 让我们先核实这说法
Who was it, that at the very moment you had a notorious pirate safely behind bars,
到底是谁 在你把臭名昭著的海盗 放心地关到监牢的时候
saw fit to free said pirate and take your dearly beloved all to hisself?
乘机放走了海盗 把你的心上人据为己有?
So whose fault is it, really,
所以 到底是谁的错?
that you've ended up a rum-pot deckhand what takes orders from pirates?
让你沦落为酗酒的低等水手 听命于海盗?
Enough!
够了！
Unfortunately, Mr Turner, he's right!
不幸的是 特纳先生 他是对的！
Still rooting for you, mate.
我还是支持你的 伙计！
We got it! We got it! We got it!
我们拿到了！
Hello, poppet.
你好啊 小妹妹
Come on, run!
冲啊！冲啊！
Sword! Sword! Sword!
剑！剑！剑！
Sword!
剑！
Follow my voice. Follow my voice.
跟着我的声音 跟着我的声音
To the left... no, turn around.
往左...不 转回去
Go to the right.
往右点
No, that's a tree.
不 那是颗树
Shut it.
闭嘴
Jar of dirt!
这罐土！
Right.
对了
We've got it!
我们得到了！
Come on, Turner!
来吧 特纳！
Leave him lie! Unless you plan on using him to hit something with.
让他躺那儿！ 除非你要用他砸人
We're not getting out of this. Not with the chest.
我们逃不掉了 带着箱子就无法脱身
Into the boat.
上船
You're mad! Don't wait for me.
你疯了！ 不要等我
I say we respect his final wish. Aye!
我说我们该尊重他的临终愿望 对！
Your bravery is wasted.
你的勇敢算是白搭了
I shall pry the chest away from your cold, dead hands.
我会从你冰冷尸体的手中拿过亡灵箱
Here you go!
拿去吧！
Pirates!
臭海盗！
What happened to the chest? Norrington took it to draw them off.
亡灵箱怎么样了? 诺灵顿带着它引开了他们
You're pulling too hard! You ain't pulling hard enough!
你拉得太用力！ 你用力得不够！
Where's the commodore? Fell behind.
司令官哪里去了? 落在后面了
My prayers be with him.
让我为他祈祷
Best not wallow in our grief.
不过还是要节哀顺变！
The bright side is you're back, and made it off free and clear.
幸好你回来了 毫发无伤
Lord on high, deliver us.
天父在上 保佑我们！
I'll handle this, mate.
我来处理这事 伙计
Oi, fishface!
死鱼脸！
Lose something? Eh? Scungilli!
丢东西了吧?
Got it!
没事！
Come to negotiate, eh, have you, you slimy git?
来谈判的吧? 你个欠揍的家伙
Look what I got.
看看我手上是啥
I got a jar of dirt. I got a jar of dirt
我有一罐土 我有一罐土
And guess what's inside it?
猜猜里面是什么?
Enough!
够了！
Hard to starboard. Hard to starboard!
右满舵 右满舵！
Brace up the foreyard!
升船头帆！
Hard to starboard!
右满舵！
Send his beloved Pearl back to the depths.
把他心爱的珍珠号送回地狱去
She's on us! She's on us!
敌火来袭！敌火来袭！
Let them taste the triple guns. Aye, Captain.
让他们尝尝三联炮 是 船长
Make fast!
绑牢固了！
Go on, me darling! Show us what you've got!
加油啊 亲爱的！ 让我们看看你的实力！
Come on, girl!
快点儿！
She's falling behind! Aye. We've got her!
它被甩掉了 对 我们把它甩掉了
We're the faster? Against the wind, the Dutchman beats us.
我们的船快? 逆风的话 他们快
But with the wind... We rob her advantage.
不过现在顺风... 我们占优势
Aye.
对
We're out of range!
我们超出射程了
Break off pursuit, run her light and douse canvas!
停止追击 降下帆！
We're giving up, sir?
我们放弃了?
They're giving up!
他们放弃了！
My father is on that ship.
我父亲在那条船上
We can take her. We should turn and fight.
我们能赢 我们应该回头战斗
Why fight when you can negotiate? All one needs is the proper leverage.
能谈判时干吗要战斗? 只需要有足够的优势就行了
Where is it? Where is the thump-thump?
去哪儿了? "砰-砰"去哪儿了?
We must have hit a reef!
我们肯定撞到礁石了！
No. It's not a reef! Get away from the rail!
不 那不是礁石！ 离开船舷！
What is it? The kraken.
是什么东西? 是挪威海怪
To arms! Load guns! Defend the mast!
准备战斗！ 那好枪！保护桅杆！
It'll attack the starboard. Run out the cannons and hold for my signal!
它会从底下攻击 上炮位 等我信号！
Easy, boys!
放松点 伙计们！
Will?
威尔?
Steady! Steady.
稳住！稳住
Will! Hold. Hold.
威尔！ 稳住！稳住
I think we've held fire long enough.
我们等得够久了
Will! Fire!
威尔！ 开火！
Lt'll be back. We have to get off the ship. There's no boats.
它会回来的 我们得离船 没有小艇了
Pull the grates. Get all the gunpowder onto the net in the cargo hold!
拉起壁炉！ 把所有火药放进货舱的网兜！
Whatever you do, don't miss. As soon as you're clear.
不管怎样 不要射失 等你准备好我就开枪
We are short-stocked on gunpowder! Six barrels!
我们火药不足 只有六桶了！
Hurry up!
快点儿！
There's only six kegs of powder! Then load the rum.
火药只有半打了！ 那就装郎姆酒
Aye, the rum too!
好吧！郎姆酒也上！
Step to!
赶紧！
You coward.
你这个懦夫
Not good.
不太妙
Haul away! Heave!
拉上去！ 拉！
Heave like you're being paid for it! Put your backs into it!
使劲拉上去！ 用尽全力！
I got you! I got you! Don't let me go!
我抓住你了！我抓住你了！ 不要抛弃我！
I won't let you go! Shoot me!
我不会抛弃你的！ 向我开枪！
Clear? Higher! Higher!
准备好了? 往上走！往上走！
Here! Come on!
这边！快来啊！
Come and get me. I'm over here!
来抓我 我在这里！
Come on!
快！
Shoot! Elizabeth, shoot!
开枪 伊丽莎白 开枪！
Did we kill it?
我们干掉它了吗?
No. We just made it angry.
没有 我们只是激怒了它
We're not out of this yet. Captain, orders!
我们还没解脱 船长 下命令！
Abandon ship. Into the longboat.
弃船 上小艇
Jack. The Pearl.
杰克！这是珍珠号
She's only a ship, mate.
她只是条船 伙计
He's right. We have to head for land.
他是对的 我们必需登陆
It's a lot of open water. It's a lot ofwater.
还有很宽的水面 还很宽啊
We have to try. We can get away as it takes down the Pearl.
我们必需试试 如果它要毁掉珍珠号 我们还能逃脱
Abandon ship.
弃船
Abandon ship or abandon hope.
放弃船 或者放弃希望
Thank you, Jack.
谢谢你 杰克
We're not free yet, love.
我们还没有脱身呢 亲爱的
You came back.
你回来了
I always knew you were a good man.
我就知道你是个好人
Prepare to cast off. There's no time to lose.
准备跳吧 没时间可以浪费了
Come on, Will. Step to!
赶快 威尔 往下走
It's after you, not the ship.
它是在追杀你 不是这船
It's not us.
不是我们
This is the only way, don't you see?
只有这个办法 你明白吗?
I'm not sorry.
我不觉得内疚
Pirate.
你这个海盗
Where's Jack?
杰克在哪?
He elected to stay behind to give us a chance.
他决定留下 给我们个机会
Go!
出发！
Bugger. Bugger, bugger.
混蛋 混蛋 混蛋
Come on!
快！
Just got it. Come on.
正好 快点
Not so bad.
还不算太糟
Hello, beastie.
你好 小怪兽
Jack Sparrow, our debt is settled.
杰克・斯派洛 我们的帐一笔勾销了
The captain goes down with his ship.
船长与船同沉
Turns out not even Jack Sparrow can best the devil.
就算杰克・斯派洛也不能战胜魔鬼
Open the chest.
打开亡灵箱
Open the chest. I need to see it!
打开亡灵箱 我要亲眼看到！
Damn you, Jack Sparrow!
该死的 杰克・斯派洛！
The last of our ships is returned.
我们最后一条船回来了
Is there any news on the chest?
亡灵箱有何消息?
None. But one of the ships did pick up a man adrift at sea.
没有 不过在海上救起一个人
He had these.
他身上有这个
I took the liberty of filling in my name.
我冒昧地填上了我的名字
If you intend to claim these, then you must have something to trade.
你想要的话 就得有东西来交换
Do you have the compass?
你拿到罗盘了?
Better.
比那更好
The heart of Davy Jones.
戴维・琼斯的心脏
Against the cold
酒可御寒
and the sorrow.
也能解忧
It's a shame.
真是遗憾
I know you're thinking that with the Pearl
我知道你以为只要有了黑珍珠号
you could have captured the devil and set free your father's soul.
就可以去擒住恶魔 救回你父亲的灵魂
Doesn't matter now.
已经无关紧要了
The Pearl is gone,
珍珠号完蛋了
along with its captain.
连同它的船长
Aye.
对
And already the world seems a bit less bright.
这世界已经灰暗了一点
He fooled us all right till the end,
他一直都在欺骗我们
but I guess that honest streak finally won out.
但最后他的良心还是胜出了
To Jack Sparrow.
为杰克・斯派洛干杯！
Never another like Captain Jack. He was a gentleman of fortune, he was.
再也不会有第二个杰克船长了 他是位绅士
He was a good man.
他是个好人
If there was anything could be done to bring him back...
如果有什么可以救他回来的
Elizabeth. Would you do it?
伊丽莎白 你会去做吗?
What would you...
你会去做么?
What would any of you be willing to do, hm?
你们都愿做么 嗯?
Would you sail to the ends of the Earth and beyond
你们会航行到天涯海角
to fetch back witty Jack and him precious Pearl?
去找回杰克和无价的珍珠号?
Aye.
是
Yes.
Aye.
是
All right.
那好
But if you go and brave the weird and haunted shores at world's end,
如果想去奇异而又充满牛鬼蛇神的天涯海角
then you will need a captain who knows those waters.
你们就需要一位称职的船长
So tell me, what's become of my ship?
说 我的船怎么样了?